Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Euro-Advertising Holding B.V. Records, 1979-1985 RL.11123
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Euro-Advertising Holding B.V. records
1979-1985
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Euro-Advertising Holding B.V.
RL.11123
2.4 Linear Feet
Established in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Euro-Advertising Holding was formed as an independent subsidiary in 1980 to manage relations among JWT offices in Europe. It was dissolved in 1985.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically
Biographical / Historical
Euro Advertising Holding formed in 1980 as Euro Advertising International (EAI). In 1982 EAI London merged with Landsdowne and joins JWT Group. In 1983 Recla-Jenssen was sold back to management. In 1984 EA Lyon joined JWT France. EAI's remaining assets were sold in 1985 and the firm was dissolved.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Euro-Advertising Holdings B.V. records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Related Materials
For related materials see the J. Walter Thompson Company London and Frankfurt Office records.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1979-1985 and includes clippings, correspondence, administrative and financial reports, minutes of Board of Director meetings, publications and other printed materials. Countries represented include the Benelux countries, France, Germany, Great Britain, Greece, Italy and Switzerland. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Advertising -- Europe; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- France; Advertising agencies -- Italy; Advertising agencies -- Germany; Advertising agencies -- Switzerland; J. Walter Thompson Company. Euro-Advertising Holding B.V.
- Euro Advertising Holding, 1979-1985; 1
  - Athens, 1981-1984 (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1980-1985 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1983; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Dusseldorf, 1982 (Box 1)
  - EA Update, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Financial reports, 1981 (Box 1)
  - International financial review, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Investment planning report 1981-1985, 1980 (Box 1)
  - London, 1981-1983; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Lyon, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Lyon, 1981-1982; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Management assessment, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Paris, 1980-1985; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Profile publications, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Publications, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
  - Planning documents, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Share Acquisition--EA Italy and Greece, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Share Acquisition--EA London and Dusseldorf, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Share Acquisition--EA Lyon and Elan, ARC, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Share Acquisition--EA Paris Tying Agreement, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Share Acquisition--EA Switzerland and Benelux, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Share Acquisition--Recla-Janssens Advertising BV, 1981 (Box 4)